Hargun Bedi . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent Software Engineering graduate from McMaster University, currently working at Jarvis Consulting Group. My academic and professional journey is characterized by my passion for technology and problem-solving, and continuous learning which is evident in my various internships and projects. These experiences have enabled me to gain experience with full-stack web development, QA automation, cloud development, and machine learning. Among my notable projects, I developed a scalable e-commerce website using a microservices architecture with technologies like Node/Express.js and AWS. Motivated by the practical experience I encountered through this project, I am also currently pursuing the AWS Associate Developer Certification to further deepen my understanding and in cloud-based solutions and technologies. In terms of my professional experience, during my internship as an Application Programmer, I significantly contributed to automated testing processes and played a vital role in ensuring efficient project delivery and my role at Develop For Good involved implementing revamped webpages for a non-profit website using React.js and MUI. These experiences reflect my adaptability, dedication, and desire to learn in contributing effectively to diverse software development environments.

Skills

Proficient: Java, JavaScript/TypeScript, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, HTML/CSS, Git

Competent: Python, Docker, React.js, Node/Express, Flask Familiar: AWS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Jenkins

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_HargunBedi

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Developed a MVP for the Jarvis Linux Cluster Administration (LCA) team, enabling management of a cluster of multiple Linux servers. This project captures hardware specifications and real-time server usage, storing information in a PostgreSQL database for analytics and resource planning. Implemented bash scripts for data collection, utilized Docker for PostgreSQL setup, and used Git and GitHub for version control.

Highlighted Projects

AZ-Shopping [GitHub]: Developed a scalable e-commerce website employing micro-services architecture and various technologies including Node/Express.JS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and React. Implemented AWS S3 for image storage, used Docker for deployment on Beanstalk, and established a CI pipeline with Jenkins on an EC2 instance.

Indeed Keyword Scraper [GitHub]: Developed a web scraper that scrapes Indeed for jobs matching a job title, location and keywords present. Leveraged Python and BeautifulSoup for extracting and transforming the scraped the data. Developed a front-end to gather input and display results using React.js and TypeScript. Developed an API using Flask to facilitate communication between the front-end and back-end.

Waste Segregation Classifier [GitHub]: Deployed a Convolutional Neural Network model based on the ResNet50 image classification architecture to help users segregate waste into appropriate bins, using PyTorch. Developed a front-end to gather input and display results using React.js. Deployed the model through a Flask-based API running on a Docker container.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (Oct 2023 - present): Developed software solutions for internal use and external clients. Engaged regularly with a dynamic team through daily stand-ups, synchronized on progress, and provided mutual support. Collaborated within a team that was rooted in continuous improvement, emphasized through frequent code reviews, skills assessments, and knowledge sharing.

Software Engineer, Develop For Good (Jun 2023 - Aug 2023): Revamped a not-for-profit organization's website for enhanced visual appeal using React.js and Material UI, and implemented a newsletter feature using a MySQL database and a REST API in Node.js/Express.js.

Application Programmer Intern, Ontario Ministry of Education (May 2021 - Aug 2022): Developed efficient VBScript-based automated testing scripts specifically for Ontario's Program Approval & Registration Information System. I optimized Smoke and Regression test report generation which led to faster reporting of critical bugs. I also used SQL queries to manipulate data, creating robust test data sets for more accurate and comprehensive testing. Additionally, I

was an active participant in daily stand-up meetings and adhered to Agile methodologies to ensure the smooth delivery of projects.

Data Analyst, Inergi LP (Jun 2019 - Aug 2019): Led the automation of supplier data validation using Python, achieving a 50% improvement in process efficiency, significantly saving time and resources.

Education

McMaster University (2018 - 2023), Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering - Summa Cum Laude - 2x Dean's List - GPA: 3.8/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Playing/watching Basketball My favourite teams are Toronto Raptors and Los Angeles Lakers. My favourite player is LeBron James.
- Photography I like nature and street photography
- Working out at the gym I primarily do strength training